yeah so I think one thing that's
definitely going to happen is that this
like notion of full stack developer is
going to become more true because if we
don't look into the future right now the
models are all commoditized like Google
anthropic they all have essentially
equally good models so they have that
backdrop of commoditized models they're
going to get cheaper to invoke and in
order to make products good on them they
actually need access to more data and my
impression is that people underestimate
how much proprietary data they have
access
to you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Applause]
[Music]
Tesla hi there and welcome to another
episode of the AI native developer on
today's episode we're actually going to
be showing you a an episode that was
from the AI native Devcon and this is
actually one of the Keynotes from mol oé
who is the CTO of Vel and and mol is
going to be talking with Dion Almer who
is the field tto of tessle and when this
session came on the conference I saw a
ping in one of our chats from a guy I
massively respect who says this guy
speaking malol he is perhaps the single
best web engineer on the planet and so
when someone says that I listen to this
session and in in this episode mul will
be talking about forel's place in the
disruptive world of llms and he talks
about how when we play with chat GPT
it's great with creating text and
generating text but it's not necessarily
good at creating web pages so uh this
one of the cell's challenges was really
about creating that user experience to
build web pages and and that's a hard
part not just the piece that allows NM
to actually create websites that make
sense but what does that UI look like
with a developer trying to actually
build that is it chat is it something
different and and mol will talk about
the AI SDK which Vel created and this is
a couple of things that is mentioned in
one there's the discussion about that
creating that abstraction layer for
effectively the apis of existing models
if you're using open AI or if you're
using anthropic if you want to switch
between the two you want to do that with
the least disruption on your code and
and your interactions as possible so
there's a number things which it does
including code streaming things that
people tend not to want to write by
themselves and that allows for that
model switching to be as I mentioned far
less painful uh one of the examples that
was given is it's like JBC uh for the
'90s and the second thing which multe
mentions as part of this AIS SDK is how
you can connect a a developer UI with
the llm in the background and this was
really interesting whereby we don't just
want to pass text to the AI to the llm
and get text back we might want to
interact in different ways for example
if I ask a question I might want a react
component back as an answer or for
example if I interact with a react
component on a web page I want that
interaction to be represented and sent
to the LM depending on what I do this is
a really great session with molta and I
hope you enjoy it so over to Dion and
multe thanks so much for for taking the
time to chat with us a little bit about
AI development I know that Vel has gone
through through and has built some
really cool AI developer tours and
you've gone through some interesting
changes there so excited to learn a
little bit about that with you so to
start with if we could go back in time a
little bit before we go to where we are
now and into the future I was curious
about when the birth of this form of the
AI Revolution kind of kicked in for you
like when did it first hit you were you
skeptical at first and was there an aha
moment where you like oh maybe there's
actually something to this llm thing so
I joined for sell it's now almost been 3
years which was that was early 2022 and
it hadn't happened yet but I also came
from Google where I think Sunder
declared the company AI first maybe 2018
and I had spent a lot of time with this
stuff there was some internal things
going around where people got really
confused about you know how good these
AIS were getting and so I was like
primed on it but then I think I went
through the same Transformations
everyone else where you try chat gbt and
you realize holy crap this is it this is
going to happen and then when you're at
versel and then that's all kicking in I
assume that the kind of the company
gathered together a little bit to see
what does this mean to us what was that
like what came out of that we've been
going through it through many dimensions
the first thing we really got lucky
actually that was my first project
getting it to Market it had been under
way we changed our function execution
infrastructure to be built on a net CPU
basis and that was done for all kinds of
reasons but when one minute AI API calls
came out it was an incredible
competitive advantage to have this
product in our hands which was really
good at this and that's where we just
got lucky because it was literally done
the moment people suddenly wanted to do
this but obviously we had to like think
about There's A disruption going on I
think we're in the broader like
developer experience space where fair to
say it's the early adopter for like more
advanced AI transformation and so we
absolutely were thinking about what's
our place in this world and I'm so happy
with our answer because I feel super
native to what we do we're a framework
company we we make next we support spel
and many other Frameworks like on the
JavaScript side and so it was obvious
that we should make a framework for
building AI applications so that's the
AISD which has been incredibly
successful in the kind of typescript
community for building AI applications
and our angle there was to say okay
there is some stuff out there from other
companies but it feels really like
framework and advanced but nobody knows
what application people want to build so
you can't build a framework yet it's too
early so with the aisk it's kind of it's
lowlevel utilities that you're going to
need but it's doesn't like prescribe you
about anything so that was our angle
number one and the angle number two was
vzero which is our kind of tool for
getting people started on front of
development getting projects kicked off
and having an expert system for the
Frameworks that we support and so again
like that's a relatively obvious thing
that I think makes sense for us to do
and thankfully it's very successful got
it awesome yeah can you explain a little
bit more what v0o actually is and and
how it really came about and and grew
and got good and it actually has gone
through a bunch of ations but the
initial one was that I think like
everyone who was think thinking about
the space is you had jbt jbt was in llm
let's squ a text and HTML is just text
so everyone was obviously you need these
guys to like go and make web pages and
but the thing was if you tried like a
year and a half ago it would not do a
good job it would make something crappy
that would look ugly and didn't work and
that was like one of the craziest insid
so we had a few folks in San Francisco
who pretty REM company but everyone was
in the same room and we're hacking a
little bit and someone like literally
raised their harm and so was like hey
hey hey I I got it to work it's good
like I have the AI it makes web pages
and and it looks amazing so that was a
good moment but then I realized that
apparently that was the easy part like
getting a user experience together that
would actually make sense to developers
took us like actually quite a while
quite a bit of ination because we
started with just hacking a chatbot to
be in this form and then we we actually
came out shipping something that looked
quite different different that was very
visual focused but I will also admit
that a year later roughly we move back
to more of a chat interface so we're
still figuring out with the right us
experiences but that was our journey
just literally yesterday we shipped a
pretty major release that changes vzer
to be able to build full applications
and have like real-time preview while
you iterate it on the kind of chat
interface and then the ability to deploy
them to production as well it has access
to like your versel environment variable
so it can just vary your database all
these things like it's pretty pretty
exciting stuff that's awesome that
initial kind of it's actually working
moment was that based on new models new
prompting what enabled that initial I
think this is actually going to maybe
work so I think the inside that we had
were discovered literally because it was
in the AI right the inside was and it's
such a crazy coincidence that it worked
is that AIS are good at Tailwind which
is this new CSS framework or we have
writing CSS where you actually write all
the CSS in classes where like this every
CSS El has a class Associated and you
just write it out it's basically inline
CSS in a slightly more sustainable way
than inline CSS so this was at a time
where open AI was leading the pack but
they had a model for the longest time
you probably remember the precise cut
off day was was December 2021 or
something like that and and so the
coincidence is that Tailwind at that
moment exists and it's popular but it's
not like today today it's like super
popular but it's already popular so
there's enough train in data like in the
model that it actually is good at this
and the kind of the Insight is that the
models of that time at least they were
really bad at saying okay I'm going to
write some CSS and I'm GNA write their
right HTML the other way around like it
wouldn't work but it could re do it
really well in one goal because it's all
now one bundle and so that was the the
step function that while generation was
bad Tailwind generation inside of HTML
was really good and so that was the
unlock that went from this crap to oh no
this is actually going to be a thing
that's so interesting because I've often
wondered about the what is The Sweet
Spot of data for some of these things
around if you have something that's
really popular but it's popular with the
masses so much that kind of the average
of it is like kind of meh versus
something that's a little bit not quite
as popular but the code that has been
written with it has been written by like
the early adopters maybe more expert
coders so maybe it can be really good
versus something brand new where there's
just nothing in the training data going
to have King makers happening I wonder
how it's going to evolve from here there
is a possible future where there will be
less Innovation because the AI just has
picked its thing and it's not going to
learn anything new if people stop
writing legit code by themselves that's
like a thing that could actually happen
you spoke about the ux choices I
remember when I first used vzer from a
prompt I just got multiple versions to
start from instead of just having the
one and I thought that was interesting
from a standpoint of both llms are
really good at giving you multiple
options and there's variants baked in
and and everything else and also the
PTSD that I have that maybe you have a
little bit of going from the 10 Blue
Links of Google where it can hide so
many sins where if a really good result
is the second one that's a great result
for the human whereas if you have a
Google assistant or Alexa where it like
comes back with its one result and it's
not perfect you lose trust was that
something that was also thought of like
early on and are there other ux choices
that you've made that like work well
within this probabilistic world that we
have with llms yeah I feel like lots of
this actually just related to also the
how the quality of the llms and and how
good people are prompting and the
introduction of multimodal they all
changed something about this so when VOR
came out multimodal model weren't really
a thing and so you couldn't upload a
design you couldn't say hey make me this
but get the vibe of this which is like a
very good prompting technique for VZ
these days but that wasn't around and
people would just say I want a dashboard
for x and if you would do that you want
to add a little bit of creativity but
you don't know what they want so that's
that really helps to make full version
and and hoping that one of them is going
to be good yeah the notion of like
elaboration I think is fascinating and
and even subtle things like I was
surprised in a tool that I built before
where I assume that developers have been
using chat GPT type things and we'll
start just chatting away and a lot of
them would just do new chat session zero
shots from scratch and so by adding to
the bottom of every chat like a question
asking for more taught them how to do it
and allowed you to collaborate and so it
feels like a fun stage again where we're
still relearning or learning new things
to be able to make this stuff actually
work yeah I think everything's moving so
fast and in like in ways that really
change what you can and need to build on
a product side because there's a lot of
competition people will immediately
clipse you if you don't actually pick up
the the latest tech yeah that's awesome
okay so back to the AIS SDK can you go a
little bit deeper on what it is and I
know it also had a recent I think 4.0
release as you're constantly shipping as
per usual yeah it like the aiska
basically I would say does two things
high level one is really just an
abstraction layer for the various model
apis out there with a focus on kind of
getting the streaming code that nobody
runs to write themselves to be just done
and we've been iterating and it has lots
of Json forcing related features lots of
tool calling related features and lots
of kind of harmonization between models
because as for example model X would
maybe sh native support for something
model B doesn't have it but if you a i a
k you can still switch between them
because the API as exposed through the
SDK is the same for both even if the
underlying implementation is is quite
different so that's the one thing which
is basically just utilities for
connecting to llms and and abstracting
that just a little bit really just a
little bit like jdbc in the 90s for
databases it's not an omm right at this
layer it's like really just saying
there's a way to talk to the database
doesn't matter way you talk to anthropic
or open AI both are exactly the same and
so that's that thing the other side that
we are heavily investing in is this
notion of connecting UI and Ai and maybe
sometimes confusing we call it
generative UI and maybe if you think
about what vzer does that's like very
specifically generative UI that's not
what we're talking about here like the
example app for example that we use is
one where you let's say you asked the
airlines AI that you want to change your
seat and then it responds with a seat
map and then you pick a seat and then
the AI knows what you just did and so
this whole cycle of having UI State
having AI State having llms that don't
really know what this UI is that
marshalling between those things is
something that we invest in as a second
big layer in the AISD got it makes sense
and so does that tie into the tool use
and function calling side of things to
be able to integrate these things
together yeah exactly so there are
several ways of doing it but like one
way is that if you use react where
components are just functions you can
literally return react components from
Tool calls and so let's say you the
simplest example is you ask the AI
what's the weather and so the AI will
invoke the get weather function but that
returns a react component to show you
the sunshine and for clouds whatever
that's one way to do it and then for
more complex cases once you make a
change that's done being you write a
little function that says okay if the
user selected seat 17c that is literally
you write a function that translate that
into the user selected seat 17c so the
llm knows what's going on because
obviously it doesn't really understand
what you click on the UI that makes
sense I'm thinking about the jdpc
metaphor or comparison that you talking
about earlier and that makes a ton of
sense now with respect to swap out the
jdbc driver but you're using SQL you so
you can't just point it to any old
database and have it work and the same
thing if you swap out the model between
an open AI model and an anthropic one
that doesn't necessarily mean you're
going to get you know the same
capabilities necessarily also just like
different results how do you see people
playing around with different models
with the SDK yeah so I think our
learnings actually somewhat like they're
surprising to me in a way the gdbc
analogies is perfect because it's really
like that we like the SQL is almost the
same right it's not the same but you can
get it very far right if you don't go
into the darkest corners of the SQL uh
language what we found is you can switch
the models that doesn't necessarily need
to be true right it could be that and
I'm talking about real applications but
people have spent months in like fine
tuning the prompt to do something
specific to like to handle all kinds of
Ed Edge cases and our experience is that
basically I'm not saying it's like
trivial to change the model but it is
like easier than at least I would have
expected like it's you can talk about
how to ideally do it IDE you have evals
that tell you how well you do and then
you iterate on it but even basically if
you don't if you're not so sophisticated
like we just found that it's like it
seems daunting and then apparently they
all converged like enough that it seems
to be an option that's really
interesting because yeah I think I would
have maybe because if you spent so much
time prompt engineering the hell out of
something and you feel like you've got
something that's working really well you
feel like oh man if I switch from you
know open AI over to anthropic all of
that work could be wasted right but if
you're saying that's not what you're
seeing in practice that's actually
awesome because it means I can like if
I'm using Sonet 35 and I prefer The
Vibes in general I can make that switch
earlier and maybe not feel much of the
pain it also obviously ties into the
kind of eval side that you're talking
about where you know we learned or
relearned the power of building
automated tests in the pre llm world uh
and I know you've spoken and and posted
about the llm world version of this
which is eval driven development can you
talk about what that looks like and how
to actually build in feedback loops and
like into building real AI applications
interesting background is because I used
to work on search we would have eots
right that's literally how Google works
and they would be human based and this
is one of the the interesting takes if
you look look at Google's upex people
obviously know about the the data
centers although that's mostly capex
right you have to pay for the power
basically and but at least when I was
there very incredibly large amount of
money was being spent on humans who
would look at search results and rate
them by the hundreds and thousands of
queries so it was straight side by side
rate which one which one's better maybe
at why right and then do it over and
over again that method like more or less
translates right to llms what is I think
the big difference is that now you can
use llms to do the rating and they are
really good at it because everyone knows
is that you have the situation where the
LM does something and then you ask it
and oh my God yeah now you mention it
right like it's just possible to write
to have good if you know the answer and
then it's really easy to get an LM to
grade how well the other llm did right
and so you can automate test it's
basically like unit tests but obviously
because LMS are involved it's got slow
so like you do have to take a bit of a
step back I feel that always happens
when something truly new is going on
don't want to talk too much about Google
but like for the longest time there was
just no automated testing for any of the
Android apps that the company was making
and these are like vilon user products
and so we're in the same stage where
that's just I forgot about it but no
actually I think we're doing better
right everyone understands that eils are
needed but they are more difficult to
implement than unitest for Android apps
it's definitely a challenge it's not
fast we use Brain Trust we're happy
customer but also Al it is in similar to
the aisk being not Ultra opinionated
Brain Trust is not Ultra opinionated
about this it's not like a fully flashed
out SAS Product Where where they like
put you through the onboarding wizard
and then that's it right that's not yet
how it works you do have to like sck in
there and then figure things out okay
makes sense so if developers think about
what life is going to be like as a you
know AI native de as we like to talk
about it we often talk about the notion
in general in the industry of being a
t-shaped developer right like where are
you Broad and where can you go deep and
I think I saw you mentioning a little
bit about how you've used you know llm
so you have a lot of deep expertise in
areas but it's given you confidence into
even areas that you haven't gone as deep
as into and rounding yourself as a
developer what do you think life's going
to be like in the future as a developer
as all of these you know tools and
everything else get gets better for us
yeah so I think one thing that's
definitely going to happen is that this
like notion of full stack develop is
going to become more true because you if
you know in and it's very similar to the
T shaped notion right because you
probably deep on something and then the
AI can help you go and figure things out
in various different areas I think vzer
is actually a really good example there
because and literally for me because
honestly I don't have the skill myself
to take a figma file and make a web page
I don't know how to do that I can tune
CSS but I cannot go from scratch this is
not a skill I have and I've done this
for 30 years but V zero can and then it
gives me the thing I it's might not be
perfect but I do have enough skills to
to tune it so I think this is like just
super powerful for everyone to go into
domains that they don't currently feel
comfortable with and I think that's
there almost like univocally a good
thing yeah I it's been shocking
sometimes to talk to some developers
this is just like a junior developer and
okay let's say it is only a junior
developer but it's a junior developer on
everything right and it's not actually
that Junior yeah perfect recall I think
one thing that isn't a thing today but I
I Can See For example incident analysis
being a perfect use case where you where
you just answer the question okay I
understand what's broken why could it be
broken and almost certainly like some
problem like this has happened in the
past but humans aren't as good at
pattern matching versus this thing which
yeah absolutely has amazing recall yeah
another thing that sometimes comes up is
some fear that developers may have
around just like how are we going to
compete with the Fang companies people
spending billions of dollars on
Foundation models that have all of this
AI expertise am I just going to be able
to do some Thin wrapper app and and that
that's kind of it what are your thoughts
on how AI is going to help the the
little guy so to speak I'm actually I'm
super bullish and my bull case has two
angles if we don't look into the future
right now the models are all
commoditized like Google anthropic openi
and Facebook they all have essentially
equally good models and so they're going
to get
themselves down to the bottom making the
product as cheap as possible and so
forth so they you have that backdrop of
commoditized models they're going to get
cheaper to invoke and in order to make
products good on them they actually need
access to more data and my impression is
that people underestimate how much
proprietary data they have access to one
example I been giving is let's you can
be like very boring situations but say
not boring but like deep but maybe not
let's say you make forklifts no actually
better example hvx systems and because
that's a bit more mainstream so everyone
needs one and it has documentation and
right now you only give that to like the
certified installers because it's pretty
difficult to consume I think you could
build like just you don't even innovate
on ux you build an AI chatbot that does
Eli five answers based on the same
documentation that you've already
written and that you've never published
and so chat gbt has not consumed this
and so you can build this a relatively
differentiated product I'm not saying
you're going to compete with open the ey
with this right but you can you can
actually add value on top of something
that basically like that a generic chat
buet could never achieve without going
into a very broad platform strategy
which I'm not saying they're not trying
but they certainly haven't been very
successful on that angle yeah makes
sense okay I know we're coming up on
time but I have to ask since we both
spent so much of our lives on the open
web how do you think AI is going to help
or harm the web for in general or and
for web developers specifically so one
thing that I thought was very
interesting is that when the AI kind of
startup boom happened in San Francisco
has it been a year and a half ago and
and since then there was such rush and
such exciting excitement and just a like
attitude of getting things out there
that just no one had time to build
native apps like this entire notion that
you would make three versions of the
thing that you don't know is good yet
and that you're going to throw away in
two weeks because new models coming out
that just not no one was even
considering that and I think now it's
starting that people say okay yeah if my
successful product as a consumer angle
let's go make a native app like that's
coming but it was such a powerful
demonstration of how good the web is as
a medium to iterate get things out there
that I think that really changed a lot
of people's mind about what the real
priorities are and because I'm not an
anti-native guy but it's certainly the
third thing I'm doing after I have
product Market fit and after things have
settled down a little bit so and you can
talk about many other things but I think
that's a good signal that there's just
so much value in having an ephemeral
zero friction platform allows everyone
to get in front of everyone else awesome
malter thank you so much for taking the
time to chat today I could talk to you
for hours about the stuff really excited
about what you're doing at Vel and all
of the tools that you're building to to
help us do all of these great things and
yeah look forward to meeting up soon
awesome yeah it was great to see you
again and thanks for having me this
super fun thank you sounds good cheers
[Applause]
[Music]
thanks for tuning in join us next time
on the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla
[Applause]
[Music]